Lum Sadiku

DeKalb, IL

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Lum-Sadiku/0cb5f84dc2081986

Experienced energy efficiency engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the non-profit organization management industry. Highly cognitive, aware, and logical. Extremely capable of multitasking. Proficient in MS Office, AutoCAD, analytical skills, communication, administration, and management. Strong engineering professional with the ability to transmit and persuade others to follow, in purchase of an MBA degree at Northern Illinois University.

Work Experience

Energy Efficiency Engineer

Green Energy Kosovo January 2019 to April 2021

- Researched and analyzed the energy and environmental policies, addressing the challenges facing Kosovo.
- Checking and improving energy consumption of buildings.
- Lobbied for the creation, harmonization and implementation of policies and laws on energy efficiency, renewable energy, and environmental protection.
- Monitored the implementation of national policies and laws in the field of energy and the environment.
- Raised public awareness on renewable energy and environmental issues and enhancing the community's participation in decision-making.
- Provided training on energy efficiency and renewable energy.

Inventory Manager

The Parts Place

March 2020 to September 2020

- Identified and resolved discrepancies in inventory.
- Managed and maintained current inventory.
- Tracked shipments to ensure they are complete, correct, and on time.

Energy Efficiency Engineer

DE - Bonn, DE

May 2019 to January 2020

Deutsche Gesellschaft Für Internationale Zusammenarbeit - GIZ Pristina, Kosovo - Headquarters: Bonn, Germany

Energy Efficiency Engineer

- Active participation and contribution to the success of the Technical University of Berlin (TUB) Mission on Construction and Demolition (C&D) Waste in Kosovo.
- Helped my country assess the current situation of C&D Waste
- Brought forth recommendations for better control and treatment of waste fraction in Kosovo.

• This research served to provide both an academic as well as practical, on the ground, guidance to municipalities and the government of Kosovo in finding a solution to the growing illegal dump problem in the country.

Renewable Energy Engineer

Video Synthesis, Non-Governmental Organization February 2018 to September 2018

- Promoted Video-Synthesis as an alternative educational platform which is designed to promote a more attractive approach to education,
- Engaged with the community and institutions with the intention of creating videos and animations that explained different topics relevant to society, including, but not limited to science, technology, environment, and history
- Also did the research, writings, editing's, and corrections of the content.

Education

Master of Business Administration in Business

Northern Illinois University - College of Business December 2021

Bachelor of Science in Energy Engineering

University for Business and Technology January 2020